# **SAM KAMALI**

(514) 566-1376 | Sam76kam@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

## Introduction

Eager recent graduate with a solid foundation in software development, particularly in areas of Front End development. Proficient in collaborative environments, adhering to best practices while showcasing **adaptability** and a product-centric mindset. **Quick learner** and **strong team player** with relevant project experience.

#### **Skills**

- Coding: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Angular, Python, PHP, HTML/CSS, TypeScript
- Familiarity with: C#, ASP.NET, Transact SQL, Azure cloud
- **Software Knowledge:** Object-oriented design, Data Structures and Algorithms, CI/CD pipelines, Agile Methodologies, Digital Cartography, Familiarity with cloud technologies
- Technical Skills: Office 365, EUC Systems, Desktop Virtualization Systems, ITIL, Computer networking, Cisco packet tracer, VPN, Visio, VMware, SharePoint, SQL Server, TCP/IP
- Design: Figma, Adobe Creative Suite
- **Strong work ethic**: Integrity and collaborative approach to work, Ability to think strategically and to translate ideas into actions, Strong communication skills

## **Work Experience**

## **Software Developer (Front End)**

Montreal, QC

Koolbaar

Feb 2023 - Feb 2024

- Designed and implemented UI/UX for Koolbaar e-commerce platform, enhancing user interaction and functionality with html/css, JavaScript.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to integrate **API**s for seamless data fetching and payment processing, resulting in a 50% decrease in transaction processing time and a 15% increase in overall site performance.

## Software Developer (Back End)

Remote

**Karbord Computer** 

May 2022 - Dec 2022

- Collaborated with the backend team to architect and implement a financial software solution.
- Utilized **SQL** to retrieve and organize data.
- Executed complex SQL queries to fetch and manipulate data, for dynamic report generation.

#### Software Developer (Front End)

Remote

Karbord Computer

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated with an agile team to enhance components for the mobile app using JavaScript frameworks such as **React.js** and **Angular** to enhance application interactivity and performance.
- Translated design mockups into functional components and Utilized Git for version control.
- Utilized design patterns to ensure scalability and reliability of front-end system.

UX/UI Designer Remote

Yekta Rose

Mar 2019 – Dec 2020

- Achieved 95% client satisfaction in gathering requirements for web development, ensuring product quality.
- Implemented web strategies with a focus on UX, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- Applied SEO techniques, contributing to 30% improvement in visibility and a 25% growth in traffic.

IT Support Specialist Mashhad, IR

Peugeot - IranKhodro

May 2017 - Feb 2019

- Conducted hardware and software troubleshooting, resolving technical issues promptly.
- Managed IT infrastructure, ensuring smooth operations and addressing data integrity concerns.
- Provided comprehensive technical support to end-users, including desktop and network support.
- Assisted in the installation and configuration of hardware, software, and operating systems.
- Utilized active directory, group policies, and organizational units to manage user accounts effectively.
- Engaged in Network and System Administration tasks to ensure network stability and security.

## **Software Developer (Azure Cloud)**

Mashhad, IR Azad University Aug 2016 - Apr 2017

- Worked under the guidance of a lead developer, contributing to the Azure cloud migration project.
- Maintained Jira stories to track progress and manage tasks effectively throughout the project lifecycle.
- Participated in the migration of applications to Azure cloud using lift-and-shift and re-platforming strategies.
- Participated in **testing** to validate migration success and ensure application performance.

## **Education**

Algonquin College Diploma - Interactive Media Design Azad University of Technology Bachelor's Degree - Computer Science

Ottawa, ON CGPA:3.9/4 Mashhad, IR CGPA:3.7/4

## **Key Projects**

- Magic Swirl: Using XD, html/css and JS, Developed a web app focusing on front-end functionality and UX.
- Pizza Order: Using React.js, created dynamic pizza ordering app with customizable sizes and toppings.
- <u>Lightbulb</u>: Developed a controller web app using **Js DOM**, featuring functions to toggle power.
- Hospital Information System (University Project): Collaborated with a team developing Hospital Information System, improving patient management and billing. Implemented design patterns for scalability.
- Al-Powered Gardening Companion (University Project): Developed a gardening website using React.js and TensorFlow.js for personalized recommendations, Deployed on Netlify for automated deployment.
- A Task Management System: Created and deployed a Task Management System with ASP.NET, Entity Framework, **Azure**, including authentication, CRUD, and responsive design.
- SMB Network: Designed and implemented SMB network infrastructure using Cisco Packet Tracer, configuring VLANs, DHCP, DNS, OSPF, ACLs, NAT, and HSRP, ensuring compliance through testing.

## **Licenses & Certifications**

Google Technical Support Fundamentals Mar 2024

Credentials ID RW4ED7J8GNTR

## ALGONQUIN COLLEGE OF APPLIED ARTS & TECHNOLOGY

## STUDENT COPY TRANSCRIPT

Student #:041-054-549 Samaneh Kamali DATE: 2024-02-22 TIME: 10:17:27

Term	Course Code	Course Title	Credit Hours	Grade
2022 Winter	PROG: 6149XWO	Interactive Media Design		
	GED0020	Entrepreneurial Mindset	42	A+
	MTM6101	Introduction to Photography	42	A+
	MTM6130	Web Development I	56	A+
	MTM6160	Digital Graphics	56	A+
	MTM6162	Design Foundations	42	A+
	ENL1813M	Communications I	42	A
2022 Spring				
	MTM6200	Video Foundations	84	A+
	MTM6201	Web Development II	56	A+
	MTM6231	Content Management Systems I	42	A+
	MTM6260	User Experience Design	56	A+
	ENL6007	Professional Communication IMD	42	A
2023 Winter				
	MGT7330	Trends in Today's Workplace	42	A+
	MTM6302	Web Development III	56	A+
	MTM6303	Content Management Systems II	70	A+
	MTM6304	Media Project Planning	56	A+
	MTM6305	User Experience Design II	56	A
2023 Spring				
	MTM6407	Web Development IV	56	A+
	MTM6461	Digital Portfolio	42	A+
	FIN2300	Introduction to Personal Finance	42	A
	MTM6404	Web Applications	56	A
	MTM6460	Applied Projects	84	A

-----

>>> GRADUATED WITH HONOURS <<<

-----

CUMULATIVE TOTALS 1120.0 4415.6

CUMULATIVE G.P.A. 3.97

Only courses for which grades were submitted appear on this transcript.

\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*

NO ENTRIES BELOW THIS LINE.